A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 FA739B
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Agro-industries and regional growth (Reports 004126), 1966 (Box 187)
  Paper developed in consultation with Douglas Ensminger for the SIET Institute Seminar in Hyderabad, Feb. 4-6, 1966. Title sufficient as abstract.
  06490423
  SIET Institute Seminar (1966: Hyderabad, India)
  Agricultural industries -- India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The rubber industry: an analysis of past and contemporary technological developments on both supply and demand for natural rubber and the implications of existing trends for Malaysian economic development (Reports 004127), 1964 (Box 187)
  Program specialist and consultant servicesfor the Foundation's program in South and Southeast Asia.
  Birth control -- Malaysia; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Delta resources development corporation (the Greenville R and D project): evaluation and recommendations (Reports 004128), 1968 (Box 187)
  06700521
  Mississippi Research And Development Center
  Extension and expansion of a demonstration training and economic development program in the Mississippi Delta.
  [National Affairs Project Evaluation series];NAPE series
  Occupational training; Vocational rehabilitation -- Delta (Miss.: Region); Endowments -- Delta (Miss.: Region); Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- Inventory of family planning communications studies (Reports 004129), 1970 (Box 187)
  L70-151
  83 p. -- 28 cm.
  Communication in birth control -- India -- Bibliography; Birth control -- India -- Bibliography; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Indian thinking and practice with urban property taxation and land policies: A critical view (Reports 004130), 1974 (Box 187)
  Study done during a seven week visit to India to review urban property taxes and the thinking concerning urban land policies.
  114 p.
  Property tax -- India; Urbanization -- India; Land use, Urban -- India
- The changing role of the Ford Foundation in relation to language education in developing countries (Reports 004131), 1974 (Box 187)
  18 p. - 28 cm.
  Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Developing countries; Language, Universal -- Study and teaching; Language policy -- Developing countries; Native language; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Proposals for trustee consideration: two research library grants from general reserve funds (Reports 004132), 1978 (Box 187)
  Research libraries -- Finance; Library information networks -- Finance; New York Public Library. Finance Committee; Council on Library Resources
- Veterans, deserters, and draft-evaders: the Vietnam decade (Reports 004133), 1974 (Box 187)
  Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Veterans -- Social conditions; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Draft resisters; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Desertions; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- United States -- Government policy; Amnesty -- United States
- Managing complex resource systems: a Foundation program for the developing countries (Reports 004134), 1977 (Box 187)
  International Division/Research & Education
  Natural resources -- Management -- Developing countries; Environmental protection -- Developing Countries; Agriculture -- Environmental aspects -- Asia; Research institutes -- Asia
- The school finance program of the Ford Foundation's education and research division (Reports 004135), 1978 (Box 187)
  An information paper for the Education Committee of the Ford Foundation Board of Trustees. --T.p.
  Schools -- United States -- Finance; Educational change -- United States; Education and state -- United States; Education -- United States; Ford Foundation. Education and Research
- The education and research division's program on sex discrimination and equality opportunity for women (Reports 004136), 1978 (Box 187)
  Women -- Employment; Women -- Education; Women -- Social roles; Sex discrimination
- The Foundation's strategy for work on population (Reports 004137), 1977 (Box 187)
  Birth control -- Developing countries -- Research; Birth control clinics -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation
- Budget policy, investment policy, and uncertainty (Reports 004138), 1977 (Box 187)
  Portfolio management; Program budgeting; Strategic planning; Ford Foundation
- Managing and financing American higher education (Reports 004139), 1977 (Box 187)
  Prepared for the Education Committee of the Board of Trustees. "A brief account of Ford Foundation activities designed to improve the administration and the economic health of higher education in America." (page 3)
  Universities and colleges -- United States -- Finance; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Management; Higher education and state -- United States; College students -- United States -- Economic conditions; College teachers -- United States; Ford Foundation
- The Foundation's strategy for work on agriculture. (Reports 004140), 1977 (Box 188)
  Agriculture -- Developing Countries; Agriculture -- Developing countries -- Research; Rural development -- Developing countries; Research institutes -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation
- Water resources development in Mexico (Reports 004141), 1969 (Box 188)
  Presented at a Seminar on Water Resources, School of Civil Engineering and Environmental Sciences, University of Oklahoma, November 19, 1969.
  11 p.: ill., maps, tables -- 28 cm.
  Water resources development -- Mexico; Hydraulic engineering -- Mexico; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The American classics revisited (Reports 004142), 1978 (Box 188)
  a packet of materials with respect to a project to encourage the publishing of the American literary classics (p. 1)
  Office of the Arts
  American literature -- Publishing; American fiction -- Publishing; American poetry -- Publishing; Philosophy, American -- Publishing; Literature publishing -- United States
- Real estate report (Reports 004143), 1971 (Box 188)
  1 v: var. pag. -- 28 cm.
  Real estate investment -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- The Ford Foundation real estate portfolio review for the three months ended May 31 (Reports 004144), 1976 (Box 188)
  Includes tables.
- An interim report on the Foundation's program of support for private Black Colleges (Reports 004145), 1976 (Box 188)
  Information paper for discussion by the Education Committee of the Board of Trustees.
  African American universities and colleges -- Finance; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- Research -- United States; Ford Foundation. Higher Education and Research
- Performance measurement and investment objectives for college and university endowments (Reports 004146), 1971 (Box 188)
  Education and Research/Higher Education & Research/Finance
  102 p. + appendices: ill., tables
  Portfolio management -- United States; Investments -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Finance; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation
- Public policy analysis: the Brookings Institution and Resources for the Future (Reports 004147), 1978 (Box 188)
  :A grant request and discussion paper.: --T.p.
  Research institutes -- United States -- Finance; Research institutes -- United States -- Mergers; Brookings Institution; Resources for the Future
- Improving communications with Cuba: an exploration of alternatives (Reports 004148), 1977 (Box 188)
  L77-98.
  25 p. + appendices -- 28 cm.
  Education, Higher -- United States -- International cooperation; International education; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Changes in Indonesia (1967-1979) (Reports 004149) (Box 188)
  07900554
  Support to enable the food research institute to undertake a commodity system study in Indonesia focusing principally on cassava.
  23 p. -- 28 cm.
  Central planning -- Indonesia; Charity organization -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; The Leland Stanford Junior University
- Reconstruction in Lebanon (Reports 004150), 1978 (Box 188)
  L76-242.
  23 p.: tables -- 28 cm.
  Disaster relief -- Lebanon; Central planning -- Lebanon; Technical assistance -- Lebanon; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Criminal defense counsel for the poor: a report for the Ford Foundation (Reports 004151), 1970 (Box 188)
  06590276
  xx, 283 p., map, tables, charts
  Legal aid -- United States; Lawyers -- United States; Legal assistance to the poor -- United States; Judgements, Criminal -- United States; Right to counsel -- United States; Criminal procedure -- United States; National Defense Project
- Desalacion: el Proceso del Futuro = Desalination, the process of the future (Reports 004152), 1969 (Box 188)
  12 p. + appendices.
  Saline water conversion
- The Central American common market: a brief evaluation (Reports 004153), 1969 (Box 188)
  27 p. -- 28 cm.
  Commercial products -- Research -- Central America; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Instituto Brasiliero de Bibliografia e Documntacao (IBBD) (Reports 004154), 1969 (Box 188)
  3 p.: table -- 28 cm.
  Academic libraries -- Brazil -- Finance; Library education -- Brazil; Librarians -- Training of -- Brazil; Universities and colleges -- Brazil; Education (Graduate) -- Brazil; Instituto Brasileiro de Bibliografia e Documentação
- Report to Ford Foundation on training of librarians in Sao Paulo School (Reports 004155), 1969 (Box 188)
  Training of librarians in Sao Paulo School
  Librarians -- Training of -- Brazil; Library education -- Brazil; Universities and colleges -- Brazil; Education (Graduate) -- Brazil; Ford Foundation. Field Office Rio de Janeiro; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Report to the Ford Foundation: Proposal for a study of library services in Brazil (Reports 004156), 1969 (Box 188)
  7 p.:table -- 28 cm.
  Proposal for a study of library services in Brazil
  Library education -- Brazil; Librarians -- Training of -- Brazil; Universities and colleges -- Brazil; Education (Graduate) -- Brazil; Ford Foundation. Field Office Rio de Janeiro; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Programming for the 70's: Ford Foundation programs in Colombia and Venezuela (Reports 004157), 1969 (Box 188)
  Charity organization -- Colombia; Charity organization -- Venezuela; Philanthropy -- Colombia; Philanthropy -- Venezuela; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- CARIFTA Caribbean Free Trade Association: its structure, current and future activities, and recommendations for a possible course of action (Reports 004158), 1969 (Box 188)
  Economic development -- Caribbean Area; Caribbean Free Trade Association
- A tentative program of educational research and experimentation for the Ford Foundation in Colombia (Reports 004159), 1970 (Box 189)
  12 p.: tables -- 28 cm.
  Education -- Research -- Colombia; Education -- Social aspects -- Colombia; Education and state -- Colombia; School attendance -- Colombia; Educational assistance -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Report on staff seminar on education and a prospectus for an education program in Colombia (Reports 004160), 1970 (Box 189)
  14 p. + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Staff seminar on education ...
  Education -- Research -- Colombia; Education -- Social aspects -- Colombia; Education and state -- Colombia; Educational assistance -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The congress Schism in India (Reports 004161), 1969 (Box 189)
  9 p. + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Presidents -- India -- Elections; Indian National Congress
- The aftermath of the Congress schism in India (Reports 004162), 1969 (Box 189)
- Aspects of social mobility in four Latin American countries (Reports 004163), 1969 (Box 189)
  30 p. + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Social mobility -- Latin America; Industries -- Social aspects; Social change -- Latin America; Ford Foundation
- The role of economics planning and management in development (Reports 004164), 1968 (Box 189)
  Notes for the Cartagena Conference.
  Central planning -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bogota; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The importance of establishing graduate programs in science and technology (Reports 004165), 1968 (Box 189)
  Science -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Colombia; Technology -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Colombia; Education (Graduate) -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bogota; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Agricultural economics in Colombia (Reports 004166), 1968 (Box 189)
  Notes for the Cartagena Conference. --p.1.
  10 p. + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Agriculture -- Research -- Colombia; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Colombia; Agriculture -- Technology transfer -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bogota; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Why education in Colombia? (Reports 004167), 1968 (Box 189)
  Education -- Colombia; Education and state -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bogota; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Ford Foundation development goals in Colombia (Reports 004168), 1968 (Box 189)
  To be discussed at Session I in Cartagena. --p.1.
  7 p. + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Charity organization -- Colombia; Philanthropy -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- A preliminary statement of the problem of political development: With some ideas on the Foundation's role in Colombia (Reports 004169), 1968 (Box 189)
  Political planning -- Colombia; Technical assistance -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Notes for Cartagena conference (Reports 004170), 1968 (Box 189, Reel R-9302)
  Population assistance -- Colombia; Birth control -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bogota; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Report to the government of Pakistan on the establishment of a foreign language teaching institute (Reports 004171), 1969 (Box 189)
  8 p. + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Establishment of a foreign language teaching institute
  Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Pakistan; Linguistics -- Study and teaching -- Pakistan; Linguists -- Training of -- Pakistan; Deccan College
- Linguistics in Pakistan (Reports 004172), 1969 (Box 189)
  17 p. + appendices: tables -- 28 cm.
  Linguistics -- Study and teaching -- Pakistan; Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Pakistan; Linguists -- Training of -- Pakistan; Deccan College
- Home economics and simple shop skills (Reports 004173), 1968 (Box 189)
  Notes for Cartagena Conference. --p.1.
  Home economics -- Study and teaching -- Colombia; Manual training -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- U.S. government development assistance to Latin America (Reports 004174), 1969 (Box 189)
  A private report to the Ford Foundation. -- T.p.
  32 p. + appendix: tables -- 28 cm.
  Economic assistance, American -- Latin America; Technical assistance -- Latin America; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The University of the Philippines: External assistance and development (Reports 004175), 1970 (Box 189)
  AP68-698.
  166 p.: tables -- 28 cm.
  Universities and colleges -- Philippines; Education, Higher -- Philippines; Higher education and state -- Philippines; Labor supply -- Philippines; Nation-building -- Philippines; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- A general theory of polarized development (Reports 004176), 1969 (Box 189)
  City planning -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Architecture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; University of California, Los Angeles. School of Architecture and Urban Planning
- Regional planning: Background and a proposed project for Western India (Reports 004177), 1969 (Box 189)
  06890088
  Advisory assistance and support for regional planning in Western India.
  29 p. -- 28 cm.
  Regional planning -- India; Central planning -- India; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- The future of community participation (Reports 004178), 1969 (Box 189)
  Prepared for the Subcommittee on Metropolitan Government in the Federal System.
  Community development projects -- United States
- The planning and operation of land distribution and land reform programs in developing countries (Reports 004179), 1968 (Box 189)
  Presented in Mexico City at the 'Seminario Internacional sobre Agricultura.' --T.p.
  International Division;ID
  31 p. -- 28 cm.
  Land reform -- Developing countries; Land tenure -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Potentials for increasing world food production (Reports 004180), 1968 (Box 189)
  Food supply -- Developing Countries; Agricultural productivity -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- A standard of excellence (Reports 004181), 1968 (Box 189)
  A draft of an evaluation of staff colleges.
  various pagings.
- Reviewing U. S. policy towards Latin America: some observations (Reports 004182), 1969 (Box 189)
  ... circulated as a discussion paper for the June 23rd [1969] meeting of the Latin America Study Group at the Brookings Institution. --p.1.
  National security -- United States; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The alliance for progress in retrospect: toward improved U.S. policies for the 1970's (Reports 004183), 1969 (Box 189)
  National security -- United States; Alliance for Progress
- A role for the land grant college in International agricultural development (Reports 004184), 1968 (Box 189)
  Paper prepared for University of Missouri Seminary, Novemer 22, 1968.
  State universities and colleges -- United States; Agricultural colleges -- United States; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States
- Field Report: Brazil, April 22 - May 2 (Reports 004185), 1969 (Box 189)
  Technical assistance -- Brazil; Endowments -- Brazil -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Observations, impressions, and review of the research programs at the Environmental Research Laboratory and the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT) (Reports 004186), 1969 (Box 190)
  Agriculture -- Mexico -- Experimentation; Agriculture -- Research -- Mexico; Corn -- Research -- Mexico; Wheat -- Research -- Mexico; Agricultural assistance -- Mexico; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Observations and impressions of the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT) in Mexico (Reports 004187), 1968 (Box 190)
  Agriculture -- Mexico -- Experimentation; Agriculture -- Research -- Mexico; Agricultural assistance -- Mexico; Corn -- Research -- Mexico; Wheat -- Research -- Mexico; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Maximizing agricultural production (Reports 004188), 1969 (Box 190)
  28 p.: ill., tables, graphs -- 28 cm.
  Agricultural productivity -- Developing countries; Crop yields -- Developing countries; Agriculture -- Developing countries -- Experimentation; Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division
- A narrative account of travels in the Far East, July 19 through August 20 (Reports 004189), 1969 (Box 190)
  Charity organization -- East Asia; Philanthropy -- East Asia; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bangkok; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The sixth meeting of the Inter-American Cultural Council, Port-of-Spain, Trinidad: June 3 to 10 (Reports 004190), 1969 (Box 190)
  10 p. + appendix: tables -- 28 cm.
  Intellectual cooperation -- Congresses; Educational assistance -- Congresses; Inter-American Cultural Council.
- Six weeks in Peru: some first impressions (Reports 004191), 1969 (Box 190)
  Political science -- Peru; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The Ford Foundation program in population (Reports 004192), 1969 (Box 190)
  Second conference of AID Administrators in the field of population.
  8 p. + tables -- 28 cm.
  Population assistance; Population research; Population policy; Birth control; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- International agricultural centers and development of indigenous institutions (Reports 004193), 1969 (Box 190)
  Discussion outline of International workshop on agricultural College and University development, Purdue University, August 2, 1969.
  4 p. + tables -- 28 cm.
  Agricultural assistance -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Research -- Mexico; Food supply -- Mexico; Ford Foundation. International Division
- South Africa: the silver linings are a figment of Munger's imagination (Reports 004194), 1969 (Box 190)
  Apartheid -- South Africa; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Aspects of social mobility in four Latin American countries (Reports 004195), 1969 (Box 190)
  30 p. + footnotes.
- The Ford Foundation: seven years in Venezuela, 1962 (Reports 004196), 1969
- The Jamaica industrial relations system: a research proposal (Reports 004197), 1969 (Box 190)
  Industrial relations -- Research -- Jamaica; Industrialization -- Research -- Jamaica; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Report to the Ford Foundation on family planning in Europe (Reports 004198), 1969 (Box 190)
  [21] p. -- 28 cm.
  Birth control clinics -- Europe; Birth control research -- Europe; Fertility, Human -- Research -- Europe; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- A survey of Black American doctorates (Reports 004199), 1969 (Box 190)
  Education and Research/Special Programs
  4 p. + attachments: tables
  Degrees, Academic -- United States -- Statistics; African American graduate students -- Statistics; Doctor of philosophy degree -- United States -- Statistics; African Americans -- Education (Graduate); Education (Graduate) -- United States
- Significant, complicated, neglected: the nutrition factor affecting Foundation programs (Reports 004200), 1979 (Box 190, Reel R-9302)
  Nutrition -- Research -- Developing countries; Malnutrition -- Developing countries; Food supply -- Developing Countries; Ford Foundation. Social Development
- Designing an evaluation of Ford Foundation assistance for a family health care project in Nigeria (Reports 004201), 1979 (Box 190)
  07690807
  Support for work in family health and population services in West Africa.
  40 p. + appendices
  Family -- Health and hygiene -- Nigeria; Medical care -- Nigeria; Public health -- Nigeria; Technical assistance -- Nigeria; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Strengthening the predominantly Negro College (Reports 004202), 1966 (Box 190)
  18 p. + appendix -- 28 cm.
  African American universities and colleges -- Congresses; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States; Ford Foundation. Higher Education and Research
- Small-scale mechanization program in Egypt (Reports 004203), 1979 (Box 190)
  A component of FF DAP 759-826. --p.1.
  07900616
  Catholic Relief Services - United States Catholic Conference Incorporated
  Small-scale farm mechanization program in Egypt.
  Farm mechanization -- Egypt; Agricultural machinery -- Egypt; Agricultural assistance -- Egypt; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- The Cajamarca-La Libertad Project in Peru (Reports 004204), 1972 (Box 190)
  A review with recommendations for an economics component. --T.p.
  38 p.: tables -- 28 cm.
  Agricultural development projects -- Peru; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Peru; Agricultural productivity -- Peru; Crop yields -- Peru; Agricultural assistance -- Peru; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Manpower, data, policy issues, and strategy in Ghana (Reports 004205), 1969 (Box 190)
  Consultant report - 1.
  Manpower policy -- Ghana; Manpower planning -- Ghana; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa